

GUS LOPES QUEIROZ

GEOSPATIAL RESEARCHER | GUSLQ.COM

ABOUT

I am a Master of Science in Geography with a BSc in Geology. Since early in my undergraduate I have been interested in geospatial research, with emphasis on processing computer complex algorithms. I am a self-taught programmer proficient multiple in programming languages, having developed several geospatial tools and methods which yielded peer-reviewed publications and presentations in events. I enjoy working in diverse group environments as well as in solo projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Academic writing
- GIS & remote sensing
- Python, Arcpy
- R, MATLAB
- C#, HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Machine learning
- Multiprocessing
- Database Query
- Photoshop
- 3D Modelling

EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH AND TEACHING ASSISTANT • UOFC • 2017 - 2019

Remote sensing research involving statistics, machine learning and programming tasks. Academic writing and <u>publication</u>. Oral presentations in events. Teaching labs and marking assignments.

INTERN IN MINERAL EXPLORATION • VOTORANTIM • 2014 - 2015

Geologic mapping, ore modelling, writing reports, database construction and maintenance, software development.

STUDENT RESEARCHER • UNIVERSITY OF CALGARY • 2014

Fieldwork and lab assistance, database development, UAV flight planning, software programming for GIS and applied geosciences.

STUDENT RESEARCHER • UFPR • 2012 - 2013

Fieldwork and lab assistance, writing, GIS analysis and coding.

EDUCATION

MSC IN GEOGRAPHY • SEPTEMBER 2019 • UNIVERSITY OF CALGARY

Graduate studies focusing on remote sensing and computer vision applied to forest mensuration on the boreal forest. My <u>thesis</u> is entitled "Remote Sensing Boreal Coarse Woody Debris".

BSC IN GEOLOGY • JANUARY 2016 • UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL DO PARANA

During my geology undergrad in Brazil I developed four geospatial tools which led to two published papers as main author and two papers as secondary author.

EXTRA

When not at work, I enjoy cycling, camping and socializing with friends in lively sessions of board games. I occasionally participate in game making marathons, having participated in eight such events since 2013.







